A doctor! Well, if he was anywhere near those explosives
when they went up...
一位博士！当他们上来的时候，如果他在那些炸药附近的话...
Yes sir. Don't you think I should go and have a look, sir?
The youngsters said he was following the cable.
是的长官。我是不是应该去看一下？
这两个年轻人说他们当时正沿着电缆在走
Yes, you'd better.
是，最好是
Sir!
是！
Oh, and Staff, take someone with you.
哦，Staff，带个人跟你一起
Sir!
是！
Father?
父亲？
Hmm...?
嗯？
The soldiers have found two youngsters in the tunnels./
士兵们在隧道里发现了两个年轻人
They seem to know a great deal about the Yeti.
他们好像知道雪怪的不少事情
Oh?
哦？
They know they're robots!
他们知道雪怪是机器人！
What!
什么！
And they know about the control spheres, too.
而且他们也知道控制球的事情
But they can't have - I mean, the public were never told!
但是不可能啊，我是说，我们从来公开过啊！
I know.
我知道
Where are they?
他们在哪儿？
Hello, hello, Holborn?... /38.5
哈罗，哈罗，Holborn？...
This is HQ to Holborn. Can you hear me?... Not a sausage.
这里是总部呼叫 Holborn．你能听到吗？...一丁点儿也没有
There must be someone manning the phone.
肯定有谁在操纵电话线
OK, Lane, what gives?
好了, Lane, 什么情况fixme
Well, it's just firing at the other end, sir.
另一端有人开火, 长官
Firing?
开火？
Yes, sir. Listen.
是的, 长官．听
Oh, good grief, no!
噢, 可怜人, 不！
Hello, HQ to Holborn?
哈喽, 总部呼叫 Holborn
What happened, Lane?
怎么了, Lane
Well, it was difficult to hear, sir.
I think the truck was late getting there...
嗯, 很难听清, 长官．我觉得手推车(fixme)没及时到达...
Then what?
那怎么？
Well they must have got the ammo unloaded, sir,
'cos he says they were jumped when they were leaving.
它们肯定把弹药卸出来了, 头儿．因为他说他们正要离开的时候它们扑过来了
Take O'Brien and a couple of the others.
带上 O'Brien 等几个人
Sir! Come on, mate.
是！快来, 伙计们
Here, you're not going out there?
你不打算出去吧？
Yes, Mr Chorley. Want to come? Report some action first hand?
出去, Chorley 先生, 你想来？想获得第一手的报道？
Well, I don't think I'd better get in the way. I.../38
哦, 我觉得我还是不要碍事的好。我...
I think I'd better stay here, don't you?
我觉得待在这里更好, 是吧？
Yes. Yes, I think you better had.
是的, 是的, 我想你最好
Father?
父亲？
But it... it can't be...
但这...这不可能啊...
Why... that's... that's over... forty years ago!
为什么...那已经是...四十年前了！
What's going on here?
这里在干什么？
Oh Jamie, don't you recognise him? It's Professor Travers.
噢 Jamie, 你不认识他了？这是 Travers 教授
So it is! Professor Travers! Here, hasn't he got old!
还真是啊！Travers 教授！看, 他没怎么变老
Huh?
啊？
Oh, but we're very pleased to see you, Professor, very pleased.
噢, 我们都非常高兴见到你, 教授, 非常高兴
The time machine... it was all true then?
这个时间机器...这么说都是真的？
The TARDIS - I mean aye, of course it's true!
Hey, do you know what's happened to the Doctor?
TARDIS - 我是说, 当然是真的！嘿, 你知道博士现在怎么样了？
Oh, is he safe?
哦, 他还安全吗？
Isn't he with you?
他没有跟你在一起吗？
No, he's in the tunnels. Arnold's gone to look for him.
Father, what is going on?
没, 他在隧道里．Arnold 去找他去了．父亲, 这是在干什么？
Oh dear, I do hope he's alright. Come on, Jamie,
let's go and find out if he's got back yet.
亲爱的, 我期望他没事．来, Jamie, 我们去看看他回来没有
Father!
父亲！
Eh? Oh, Victoria, try and explain to Anne, will you?
嗯？哦, Victoria, 你给 Anne 解释一下, 行吗？
Oh dear!
哦, 老天！
There hasn't been an explosion, Staff!
没有发生爆炸, Staff！
Oh, no - well at least, we hope not.
哦, 没有 - 至少, 我们也期望没有
I can see that, lad... Here!
我看到了, 小伙子...过来！fixts
No sign of that Doctor bloke.
没有见到这什么博士的影子
No... here, give me a hand with this.
没有...嘿, 给我搭把手
It's our detonator, alright. It's fired, too.../25.5
是我们的引爆器, 也已经引爆了...
'ere, hang on a minute. All the ammo, Staff.
If it's fired, then why didn't...
等一下, 所有的弹药, Staff．如果已经引爆了, 为什么没有...
Yeah, why didn't this tunnel go up?... No damage at all...
是啊, 为什么这个隧道没有被炸掉？...完全没受损...
Yet something blew up here!
但这里的确爆炸了啊！
It's obvious, ain't it? It's been got at.
很显然, 不是？fixme
Where's that Doctor? That's what I'd like to know.
那个博士在哪儿？这是我想知道的
Tibet? Tibet? You're joking.
西藏？西藏？你在开玩笑
That's where old Travers says they come from.
He reckons they're Abominable Snowmen.
是 Travers 说它们就来自那儿. 他管他们叫做可恶的雪人
Well, he's off his chump, ain't he?
How'd they get here in the first place?
他脑袋有问题吧, 是不？它们最开始是怎么到这里来的？
Come through the post, don't they?
邮递来的, 不是吗？
Nah, seriously. Outer space, that's where they come from.
Well that's what I reckon, anyway.
严肃点．外太空, 那是它们来的地方．这是我的猜测
Oh do leave off! You've been reading
too many kids' comics, you have!
噢, 得了吧！你看了太多小孩子的漫画书, 对不？
Alright then, Corp, where do they come from?
好吧．下士, 那他们是从那儿来的？
It's a foreign power, ain't it? Bacteriological warfare,
that's what that stuff is in the tunnels.
应该是外国势力, 对不？细菌战争, 隧道里面的东西就是这个
What, that fungus stuff?
什么, 那些真菌？
Yeah. And them Yeti are some sort of new weapon.
Well, a sort of robot army.
对, 那些雪怪就是某种新式武器, 一种机器人军队
What, you mean it ain't real then?
什么, 你是说他们不是真的动物？
Well of course they ain't, you nit!
当然不是真的, 你个废柴！
Otherwise we'd be able to knock 'em out
with the small arms, wouldn't we?
否则我们就可以用小型武器搞定他们了, 对不？
Yeah - nothing hardly touches 'em, does it?
是啊 - 没什么能搞定它们了, 有吗？
Not unless you can cop 'em straight between the eyes.
Then they've had it.
除非你直接对准它们两眼之间下手, 那它们就嗝屁了
Father?
父亲？
Hmm?
嗯？
Have you ever seen this TARDIS?
你见过 TARDIS 吗？
No, no, I can't say I have.
没, 没有, 我说不上见过
It all sounds a bit far-fetched to me.
在我听来感觉有点太不现实了
You know, I think the Doctor's at the back of all this.
你知道吗, 我觉得这一切都是博士在背后捣鬼
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Doesn't it strike you as odd that on the two occasions
you've encountered the Yeti, you've also come across the Doctor?
你就从来没有觉得奇怪, 你两次遇到雪怪, 你都碰到了博士？
Well?
怎样？
Well, it's obvious - he controls them!
这, 很显然 - 他在控制他们！
Oh, but surely...
哦, 但当然...
What? Oh, tea. Thank you, my dear.
什么？哦, 茶．谢谢你, 亲爱的
Oh, aren't you having any?
哦, 你不喝点吗？
No, I think I'll go and lie down for a bit.
不了, 我想我要去躺一会儿
Good idea.
好主意
Do you think she heard?
你觉得她听到了吗？
No... in any case, what you say is nonsense, Anne./14.5
不管怎么说, 你说的都是胡扯, Anne
I saw the Doctor defeat those robots and save Detsen Monastery. /19.7
我看见博士打败了那些机器人, 拯救了德赞寺
He wouldn't do that if he was in league with them, now would he?
如果他跟它们是一伙的, 他不会那么做的, 现在他会吗？
No, no I suppose not.
不, 我觉得不会
Here, Corp, look at this!
过来, 下士, 看看这个
What... oh crikey! That's what comes of talking about it!
什么...啊呀！真是说什么来什么
It's that fungus stuff, it's moving again!
是那些真菌, 它又在移动了！
Don't worry!
别担心
Can't help it - I feel... responsible somehow./49.5
忍不住啊 - 不知怎的...我觉得我有责任
If only the Doctor would turn up. I'm sure he could help us.
如果博士能出现就好了, 我肯定他能帮上我们
'Scuse me, sir...
抱歉, 先生
Eh, what?
嗯, 什么？
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again.
Euston Square's gone.
那些真菌, 又在移动了．尤斯顿广场没了
Come on, let's have a look!
快来, 我们来看看！
It's on the move again, Weams?
它又在移动了, Weams？
Yes, sir. Kings Cross has gone,
and it's moving on to Farringdon.
是的, 先生, 国王十字车站也丢了．它现在往 Farringdon 站去了
It's never moved as fast as this before!
它以前从来没有移动得这么快过！
Hasn't moved at all the last three weeks, Miss.
前面三个星期都没移动过，小姐
What started it up again all of a sudden?
是什么东西突然间触发了它？
Can't say.
不好说
Strange, isn't it, that all this should happen
on the very day that your mysterious Doctor friend turns up?
很奇怪啊，是不是，你的那位博士朋友出现的同一天，就发生了这么多事
He hasn't turned up.
他还没出现呢
Precisely. He could have sent those kids in here as spies.
的确．他可能是把那两个孩子派过来做间谍了
Rubbish! Would Jamie go away and leave Victoria,
if he didn't intend coming back again?
胡说！你说 Jamie 不会再回来, 那他会留下 Victoria 一个人吗？
Excuse me, sir, but where is the young lady?
对不起, 先生, 但那个年轻女士在哪儿？
Oh, in the Common Room, I suppose.
哦, 在公共休息室, 我估计
No she's not, 'cos I went in there when I was looking for you!
不, 她没有．我刚才找你的时候到那里面去过了！
What? Well... where is she then?
什么？那...她在哪儿呢？
Jamie? Doctor?... Jamie? Doctor?
Jamie? 博士? ... Jamie? 博士?
Victoria!
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness I found you! Are you alright?
哦, 博士, 感谢上帝我找到你了！你没事吧
Look, sir, the fungus! It's moving again!
看, 头儿, 真菌！又在移动了！
Hope the Captain and Staff Arnold
ain't anywhere near that little lot.
期望队长和 Staff Arnold 不在那个小东西的附近
Lane? Lane! Fall back, you'll never hold them!
Lane? Lane! 后撤, 你阻挡不了它们的！
Will nothing stop them?
没什么能挡住他们吗？
Come on, back!
快, 回来！
We couldn't hold 'em, sir. They're coming, two of 'em!
我们没法顶住他们, 头儿．他们来了, 有两个！
They got O'Brien and Cocksey, nothing stops them!
O'Brien 和 Cocksey 已经落入它们手上了, 没什么能挡住它们！
It's Staff Arnold!
是 Staff Arnold!
Yeah, come on.
是啊, 快来
Captain?
队长？
Yeti!
雪怪！
They got two of us!
它们抓了我们两个人！
And the ammo detail - they're all gone.
还有那些弹药, 都不见了(fixme)
What's the plan then?
那计划是什么？
I brought a load of explosives down from Holborn.
I'm going to blow it - and them with it.
我从 Holborn 那里带下来一包炸药．我打算引爆它, 炸了它们
Taking a bit of a risk, aren't you, sir?
有点风险, fixme
Yeah, I know.
是的, 我知道
Hey, look what's happening!
嘿, 看看什么情况！
What are they doing?
它们在干什么？
Looks like the cobwebs!
看着像是蜘蛛网！
Cobwebs or not, I'm going to blow it sky high. Get back!
不管是蜘蛛网还是什么, 我要把它炸到天上去．后退！
What's that noise?
那是什么声音？
The boxes are pulsating!
那盒子在脉动！
Get back!
回来！
This waiting's getting on my nerves.
Why the heck don't they do something?
这么等着让我更紧张了，他们为什么不做点什么？
Steady, lad. We'll know soon enough.
稳住, 小伙子。我们很快就会知道
We can't just stand here. Can't we make a run for it?
我们不能就这么站在这儿，要不我们跑过去吧？
We wouldn't stand a chance, not with them switched on.
我们一点机会都没有, 只要它们的开关还开着
How do you know that?
你怎么知道的？
It's alright, sir. The Professor's vouched for him.
Understand he knows a great deal about these robots.
没事的, 头儿。教授为他担保了。你要知道他对这些机器人很了解
See, you have to find out...
看，如果你想搞明白
What's that?
怎么回事？
What made them do that, I wonder?
谁让它们这样的，真奇怪
Couldn't say, sir. But I don't think we should stay to find out.
不好说，头儿。但我觉得我们不要停在这里研究这个
Yes, you're right, Staff. Come on, let's get back.
是，你说得对，Staff。来，我们回去
Wait - can we not just see what they're up to?
等等 -- 我们能不能看看他们在干什么？
No! If there's one thing that I've learned, it's never push your luck. Now come on.
不！如果说有一件事我学乖了, 那就是永远不会用光你的运气。现在赶紧
What is it, sir?
是什么，头儿？
Quiet! Listen.
安静！听
Quick, get in here.
快，到里面去
Soldier!
士兵！
Well, there's a sight for sore eyes!
啊，眼睛都酸了总算看到个人！
Are you stark raving mad?
你疯了吗？
Aye, well I always sing when I'm scared, see.
啊，我害怕的时候就总唱歌, 就这样。
Stand to attention when you're talking to an officer!
和长官说话的时候, 要立正站好！
Name and serial!
名字、番号！
6-0...
Shush!
嘘！
6-0-1 Evans, sir!
Evans? Anybody know him?
Evans？有谁认识他吗？
Oh, I'm not one of your lot, sir.
哦，我不是你们这伙的，长官
Then what are you doing down here?
那你在这下面做什么？
Trying to get out, Sarge!
在找路出去, 中士!
Don't try to be funny with me, lad!
How did you get down here in the first place?
别想跟我开玩笑, 小伙子！你一开始是怎么来这里的？
Driver on the ammo truck to Holborn. Got jumped, we did - quite a dust up, there was. /40
Couldn't get past them hairy creatures, see? Been wandering for hours. Lost, I was. /46
I tried one way, but there seemed to be some sort of cobweb muck moving down the tunnel.
Moving? Are you sure it was moving?
在移动？你确定它是在移动？
Well of course I'm sure!... sir. Sounds daft, I know, /56
我当然确定，长官。听起来有点傻，我知道
but it seemed to be following a Yeti that had a kind of pointed glass thing in its hands.
但它似乎是跟一个雪怪在移动, 雪怪手里有一种玻璃状的尖头器件
Was it shaped like a pyramid?
它是不是是角锥状的？
Well, I suppose it was, really.
嗯，我觉得是，真的
Well that's it! Smash the pyramid, and you put the Intelligence out of action!
那就是了！砸烂那个角锥，你就让大智慧没招了
What Intelligence?
什么智慧？
Whereabouts did you say this happened?
你说这是在哪里发生的？
Kings Cross, Staff.
国王十字车站，Staff
What!
什么！
Headquarters, sir - HQ may be in danger!
总部，头儿 - 总部可能遇到危险了
Yes, we'd better get back as soon as we can. Come on.
是的, 我们最好尽快回去。快来
No, look...
不，你看
Now listen to what the officer said, young man. Come on!
现在听长官的话，年轻人。快点！
Look, I came down here to find the Doctor. I'm not going back till I have!
你看，我是下来找博士的。找到他之前我不会回去！
Now look here...
看看这里...
No, I'm not going! And if I get a chance to smash that pyramid, I will!
不，我不去！而且如果我有机会砸烂那个角锥的话，我会砸的
That's quite a risk you're taking.
你这是在冒很大的风险
Aye, but it's me that's taking it.
Alright, it's your neck, chum.
好吧，这是你的脖子, 伙计FIXME
Sir!
长官！
Yes?
什么？
I'd like to volunteer to go with the young gentleman, sir.
我自愿跟这个年轻绅士一起去，长官
Well, you're not one of my lot... alright. Come on, the rest of you.
那个，你也不是我这部分的...好吧。快点，你们其它人
Monument! Then it's Tower Hill next.
Wait a minute! Did you hear something?
等一下，你听到什么了没？
What?
什么？
Listen.
听
Look! The fungus, it's here!
看，真菌，它到这儿了！
We'd better get out, fast!
我们最好出去，快！
- Jamie!  - Doctor! Good to see you!
- Jamie！ - 博士！见到你太好了